<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[George Pestell dot com]]></title><description><![CDATA[Come see what I'm up to. (It's not much). George Pestell is a computer science student from the UK]]></description><link>https://georgepestell.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 12:11:22 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Being Positive When You Don't Feel It]]></title><description><![CDATA[When you feel like shit, sometimes people can get under your skin by telling you that it'll be ok if you stay optimistic. For one  reason or…]]></description><link>https://georgepestell.com/2020-05-11-positivity-when-its-tough/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://georgepestell.com/2020-05-11-positivity-when-its-tough/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;When you feel like shit, sometimes people can get under your skin by telling you that it&apos;ll be ok if you stay optimistic. For one  reason or another, someone else saying it isn&apos;t what you need. What they&apos;re are telling you is ( most of the time ) true - at least staying positive will make it more bearable. You just need to be the one to tell youself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Staying aware that you can&apos;t do much in most situations is a powerful thing because it can help you to accept whatever happens. Trying to stay positive is better than accepting the misery that you can&apos;t and won&apos;t avoid as leaning into the negativity will more likely make it seem worse and give you a dreadful sense of anticipation.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Brain Fog]]></title><description><![CDATA[As I have grown up (figuratively that is. I've always been short), I have
become more and more aware of the feeling of brain fog. What I…]]></description><link>https://georgepestell.com/2020-02-07-brain-fog/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://georgepestell.com/2020-02-07-brain-fog/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;As I have grown up (figuratively that is. I&apos;ve always been short), I have
become more and more aware of the feeling of brain fog. What I used to just
think was a lack of sleep is actually far more complex, yet useful for gauging
the benefit of different lifestyle choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was this goal for findingconsistency and mentally clarity that lead me to
finding 30 day challenges. Introduced to me through a video by freelance
film-maker/YouTuber &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube.com/user/blackboxfilmcompany&quot;&gt;Matt
D&apos;Avella&lt;/a&gt;. Usually from the
beginning of each month, and for 30 days, you chose 1 activity or change to
commit to and just focus on that one thing to add to your life. I found that
this made trying new things more interesting and stopped me over-loading myself
when I feel like I am not good enough. Real change comes from slowing down and
making small, compound changes, which overall lead to bigger changes as you
grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Just to note this obviously isn&apos;t advice. More so, this is just my
experience in trying to make my life better and you shouldn&apos;t really be
listening to me anyway.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that said: What is brain fog? In my experience, brain fog is pretty self explanatory.
Thoughts feel slow and uninspired, and despite efforts to rouse; the task of
concentrating seems near impossible without a Finnish ice bath to shock the
nervous system awake. All round it just feels bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t know the best way to tackle this phenomena. I have found real tangible
results with getting at least 7 hours sleep every night and with getting to
sleep at as consistent a time as I can maintain. Also with creating an exercise
schedule and keeping to it. Overall I think the key is just in consistency. We
adapt to what we experience on a regular basis. Obviously, continuously treating
yourself with no respect won&apos;t get you anywhere but by making decisions just to
&apos;quit&apos; after a few weeks of &apos;giving up on sugar&apos; and binging is more
counter-productive than gradually reducing sugar when you can at your own pace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve come to realize I don&apos;t need to be who I want to be at this very second.
In-fact, the goal posts are always moving because getting everything you want would make
everything instantly lose all meaning. Therefore, you naturally aim higher as
you improve so chasing the target will only lead to the feeling of
disappointment. Aiming and letting yourself get there at the pace it
takes is all you can really do whilst celebrating the small victories along the
way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ll keep trying 30 day challenges when I can. This month (Feb 2020) i&apos;m trying
to get into writing and so have written for at least half an hour every day. I
might put a section up on the projects page about my past, present and future
30 day challenges when I can be bothered ;)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Running The Strawberry Trail]]></title><description><![CDATA[This year, setting and completing goals is something I am really keen on getting done. I don't mean the set and forget new years resolutions…]]></description><link>https://georgepestell.com/2020-02-01-strawberry-trail/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://georgepestell.com/2020-02-01-strawberry-trail/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This year, setting and completing goals is something I am really keen on getting done. I don&apos;t mean the set and forget new years resolutions many of us have made in the past. I mean planned targets with a roadmap at least thought out, so hopefully I can actually complete some of them. One of the early goals I came up with is to run an ultra marathon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having run for a few years, I try to get out and run 3 times a week - slowly increasing my average pace and distance. It feels quite repetetive running without a particular event to train for so, I looked at a few local options. Around where I live there&apos;s a route standing out to me. Not a formal race with a medal or belt buckle for finishing. Just a humble set of sign posts around hampshire. This route is called The Strawberry Trail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./strawberry-trail.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Strawberry Trail Route&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strava.com/routes/23296093&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Strawberry Trail&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a &lt;strong&gt;28 mile&lt;/strong&gt; figure of 8 route centering around manor farm. Passing through fields, by landmarks and around areas heavily involved in the strawberry industry of the 19&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century. Here I have the opportunity to explore my own local history which is not really something myself or many of the people I know have done much of. It&apos;s really easy to forget that the way people live their lives is, in many ways, miles apart from how they were in relatively recent history and it feels like the ways people made the most of their lives may be able to lend wisdom to how we can find a sense of meaning in our own, despite these lifestyle changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the mid 19th century, it looks like Hedge End and the surrounding area supported a booming strawberry industry. Railway stations were constructed for the sole purpose of transporting vast quantities of the fruit across the country. The short shelf-life item demanded an efficient train system as demand was high. With over-seas imports not viable because transport times were too long without refridgeration. This lead to train stations getting built and platforms getting extended with the main aim of getting more strawberries out more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This boom lasted and proceeded for over a century but (in the 1960&apos;s), as with many fruits and vegetables and as technology caught up, international imports opened up a global marketplace and tough competition. This ultimately was impossible to overcome and still be profitable enough for the industry to survive. Thus, the old strawberry fields turned to housing and people moved on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when? &lt;strong&gt;May 16&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is probably the best time for it. The temperature is cool enough not to die of dehydration but the weather tends to be clearer than not. Also It gives me the time to get used to the longer distances and running with bottles of water. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having run a small portion of the route hundreds of times. This route feels almost like a worm-hole to another time. A glimpse of what was to be found through the same ground farmers walked and strawberries grew. I recommend people look for these signs around where they live. In the UK there are many of these sign-posts with the trail names on them and maybe you too can find some history hidden right infront of you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are &lt;strong&gt;that&lt;/strong&gt; interested, you can follow my runs throughout the year: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strava.com/athletes/19562536&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&apos;button-strava&apos;&gt;Follow Me On Strava&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/feed.xml&quot;&gt;subscribe to my rss feed&lt;/a&gt; as I think I might make some more posts about it as I progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also track my goals for the year &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>